<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dirk Jamieson</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Dirk Jamieson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 11:59:54 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://netherfoam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 11:59:54 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Want to get in touch? Email me at
dirk.jamieson@gmail.com
Or message me on LinkedIn:
https://www.linkedin.com/in/dirkjamieson/</description></item><item><title>Skills</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/skills/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 11:59:54 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/skills/</guid><description>Languages and Frameworks Java (7 years professional, plus 4 years hobby), Spring Boot (7 years) SQL (8 years professional), Postgres (7 years), MySQL (1.5 years) PHP (1.5 years professional), Symfony (1.5 years) Python (1 year professional) Services AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, SNS, SQS, IAM, more..), Auth0 Systems Ubuntu, Windows Git, GitHub, GitLab, TeamCity, Marathon, Mesos IntelliJ Suite (IDEA, DataGrip, PHPStorm, PyCharm)</description></item><item><title>Work History</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/history/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 11:59:54 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/history/</guid><description>FireSight (2023, 6 month contract) Sole developer of the project Development of GUI tools to orchestrate the execution of Phoenix RapidFire, and combine results using Python Developed a QGIS plugin with algorithms to: Analyse and export BOM weather for fire simulations Analyse historical fire danger index ratings for extreme fire danger days Analyse fire simulations and extract subdatasets: impact frequency, house loss probability, areas of interest, heatmaps and dangerous ignition zones Determine frequency of historical days suitable for safe burns Developed a Google Earth Engine App to map live fuel moisture content using MODIS satellite imagery RedEye Apps (2015-2023, Fulltime): 2020-2023 Technical Lead (Spring, Java / Python) for the RedEye Bushfire Platform 2017-2019 Backend Developer and Technical Lead (Spring, Java) for RedEye Workforce Mobility 2015-2016 Junior Developer (Symfony, PHP) for RedEye RedEye Document Management System Developed extensive REST API for web and mobile apps Responsibilities included Technical lead for a team of 2-4 developers Feature development, maintenance, optimisation, code reviews, CI/CD configuration, release management Unit testing, integration testing, manual testing Dockerisation, staging and production environment deployment in AWS Product scoping and solutionising Mentoring junior developers and providing technical and architectural guidance Academic Griffith University, Honours 2012-2016: Overall 6.</description></item><item><title>Historisk</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/historisk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/historisk/</guid><description>Background FireSight provides tailored geospatial analysis of bushfire conditions. This requires the development of custom geospatial software to help perform the analysis of environmental conditions ranging across historical weather, future forecasts and fire spread analysis.
Historisk QGIS Plugin The Historisk QGIS plugin was created to provide tools inside QGIS which allow FireSight to perform a number of tasks, including:
Historical Fire Danger Index Analysis Given the historical Forest Fire Danger Index (FFDI) for the past 30 years of data, provided by the Bureau of Meteorology, this tool builds a raster of an annual exceedance threshold value across the years.</description></item><item><title>Convexion</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/convexion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/convexion/</guid><description>
Convexion was a bushfire SaaS product that integrated bushfire tools into a web app to allow users to understand landscape scale risk with minimal friction.
Role Technical lead for the project (2019-2023), leading a development team of 4 Agile / Scrum team Hybrid remote/in person Tech Stack Java / Springboot Python / Flask / Xarray / GDAL PostgreSQL / PostGIS Docker / Mesos / AWS Domain Bushfire Landscape scale risk modelling Bushfire simulations Displaying weather and landscape state Cooperating with data scientists Challenges &amp;amp; Solutions Tiling MVT format Phoenix</description></item><item><title>Workforce Mobility</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/workforce_mobility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/workforce_mobility/</guid><description>Role Technical lead for the project (2016-2019), leading a development team of 4 Agile / Scrum team In person Tech Stack Java / Springboot / Hibernate PostgreSQL / ElasticSearch / Redis Docker / Mesos / AWS Domain Asset Management Digital twin Autodesk 3d modelling Challenges &amp;amp; Solutions Mobile &amp;amp; offline access Searching 3D model previews</description></item><item><title>RedEye DMS</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/document_management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/document_management/</guid><description> Document management system Optimised complex MySQL queries Technologies: php, symfony2, MySQL, elastic search</description></item><item><title>Runescape Server</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/runescape/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/runescape/</guid><description>Java / MySQL server Blank / New project from day 1 with goal of developing skills Great success after 4 years of work Referenced existing source code for network protocols and data formats Some assistance from the community who were also keen to learn Learned many skills Learned to maintain a codebase over a long time Plugin system added, influenced by the Bukkit server structure Scripting language with green threads for imperative programming to reduce callback hell ~55,000 lines of core code plus scripts and plugins Reverse engineering the game client Simple Server-Sided Bots Each dot represents a player which is being simulated and moving on the map to begin achieving its own generated goals.</description></item><item><title>Bukkit</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/bukkit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/bukkit/</guid><description> MaxBans QuickShop MaxBansPlus Screenshots of pages Download counters Date ranges</description></item><item><title>MaxGamer</title><link>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/maxgamer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netherfoam.github.io/projects/maxgamer/</guid><description>This was a community I operated and moderated between 2010-2014. It was a Minecraft server that started with some local players from my friend circle that were looking for a community to play with. After opening it up to the public, the community reached 75,000 unique registrations after its 5 year life span. It was a fantastic hobby project during my time studying at university where the majority of my time went into development and player relations including events and community management.</description></item></channel></rss>